Muhammad Sohail Shams



Add: Høje Gladsaxe 67, 2 TH Søborg, 2860 Copenhagen.

PH: +45 50909122

I come from a diverse background having 6 years of experience within the field of marketing management and administration. I am well organized and structured person who have a broad knowledge of working within administration, customer service, organizing meetings, employee training and marketing.

Skills:

Communication	Service Minded
Team Player	Flexible
Coordination	Open Minded
Problem Solver	Proactive
Planner	Extrovert
Execution	Result Oriented
	Innovative
	Team Player Coordination Problem Solver Planner

IT Skills:

MS Office	HTML5	CSS3/ Bootstrap
JavaScript/ JQuery	Python/Flask	Materialize

Experience:

TR Trading

Administrative Assistant July 2019 till February 2020

- Keeping accurate records of revenue and expenditures
- Daily administrative tasks
- Keeping up to date employees with the new rules and regulations
- Paying out the invoices

GURU Copenhagen, Denmark

Manager January 2011 till June 2017

- Assisting CEO to plan, develop & execute strategies
- Assisting CEO in financial issues like, sales, expense, salaries etc
- Oversee day to day operations of the restaurant
- Prepare and execute advertising or sales promotion strategies
- Respond efficiently to the written and oral inquiries of the customers
- Initiate and maintain publicity and promotions on social media
- Inventory management

City Traffic Police Faisalabad, Pakistan

Sub-Inspector Traffic Police March 2007 till August 2009

- Developed traffic strategy to manage traffic patterns during the rush hours
- Oversee first aid to the victims of accidents until paramedics arrive
- Delivering lectures on road safety and traffic laws

Apna Rozgar Toba Tek Singh, Pakistan

Volunteer October 2013 till Present

- Idea generation
- Arranging finance
- Helping people in setting up small business

Qualifications:

Linnaeus University Kalmar, Sweden

Masters of Science in Marketing, June 2010

Government College University Faisalabad, Pakistan

Masters of Business Administration, December 2007

Government College of Science Faisalabad, Pakistan

Bachelors of Science, September 2004

Research and Academic-work:

Master's thesis in Brand Building process with Norden Machinery AB Sweden

Developed a business plan of tifo.se Sweden

Analysis report on Chinese & Korean business system

Case study of Norden Machinery's matching strategy in India

Developed international marketing strategy for Norden Machinery for Indian Market

Developed a report on internationalization of SMEs

Research Project "Market-Orientation and Its Effect on Performance"

Language Skills:

Urdu	Mother Tongue
English	Fluent
Danish	High intermediate level

Extracurricular activities and interest:

- Spending time with family and friends
- Watching movies and documentaries
- Cricket